# Nicklas **Hansen**

Github: nicklashansen | LinkedIn: ncklas

📗 (+45) 61 26 46 82 | 🔤 hello@nicklashansen.com | 🎡 nicklashansen.com | 🐸 23 | 📍 Copenhagen, Denmark

## Research interest

I am highly interested in research on the generalization and robustness of deep reinforcement learning agents, particularly in connection with self-supervision, transfer learning and optimization.

I strive to make artificial intelligence available to a broader audience through research and open source projects.

## **Education**

# University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, CA

Visiting Graduate Student

Spring 2020

A semester devoted to special topics in deep learning and data-driven innovation.

Participant in Innovation Centre Denmark's SPARK program and recipient of the Spar Nord Foundation Scholarship.

## **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

M.Sc. Mathematical Modelling & Computing GPA: 10.5 (-3 to 12)

Feb 2019 -

Largely focused on special topics in deep learning such as deep reinforcement learning, deep unsupervised learning, optimization for deep learning and research on novel applications of deep learning.

# **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

B.Sc. Software Engineering GPA: 8.2 (-3 to 12)

Sep 2015 - Dec 2018

Courses in computer science, statistics, machine learning, Al and project management.

#### **Nanyang Technological University**

Singapore, Singapore

**Exchange Student** 

Fall 2017

Courses in computer vision, cryptology and large-scale software engineering.

# **Professional experience**

# **Technical University of Denmark**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

**Teaching Assistant** 

Fall 2019

02456 Deep Learning and 02454 Introduction to Cognitive Science.

I taught 6 hours a week, developed course material, corrected assignments and supervised 50+ students' projects on the topics of deep reinforcement learning and self-supervised learning.

#### **Retune DSP**

Kongens Lyngby, Denmark

Assistant Software Developer

Feb 2019 - Dec 2019

I help a team of engineers build and maintain deep learning pipelines for embedded voice control systems.

#### Raffle.ai

Copenhagen, Denmark

Machine Learning Intern

Summer 2019

I reimplemented the SyntaxSQLNet cross-domain text-to-SQL parser in PyTorch and improved its accuracy by 12%. https://github.com/raffle-interns/SyntaxSQLNet

#### **Nordic Transition**

Gentofte, Denmark

Lead Software Developer

Iul 2017 - Dec 2019

I developed and maintained a GDPR-compliant data management and analysis platform for the HR industry.

## Summer schools

# Åbo Akademi

Turku, Finland Aug 2018

Development of high-assured autonomous systems

**Tallinn Technical University** 

High-assured autonomous systems

Tallinn, Estonia Jun 2018

## **Certificates**

**Dansk Standard** 

ISO21500 Guidance on Project Management

Copenhagen, Denmark Ian 2018

To be submitted

Dec 2019

Oct 2019

Oct 2019

Jun 2019

# **Current projects**

#### Short Term Blood Glucose Prediction Based on Continuous Glucose Monitoring Data

To be submitted for IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society by Jan 2020

Pre-print available for download here: <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/13NZBZLNZ5nij5">https://drive.google.com/file/d/13NZBZLNZ5nij5</a> YBoF3tkRf9Hnr5ZAYA

A. Mohebbi, A. Johansen, N. Hansen, P. Christensen, M. Jensen, J. Tarp, H. Bengtsson, M. Mørup

# **Open source contributions**

#### **Optimization in deep learning**

Collection of recent deep learning optimization algorithms (40+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/neural-net-optimization

How to build RNNs and LSTMs from scratch with NumPy

Educational material on recurrent neural networks (100+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/rnn\_lstm\_from\_scratch

**Minimal Neural Architecture Search** 

A minimalistic NAS implementation for educational purposes (30+ stars)

https://github.com/nicklashansen/minimal-nas

Asynchronous Advantage Actor-Critic (A3C)

Implementation and ablation study of A3C on common RL environments

https://github.com/nicklashansen/a3c

# **Game development**

#### Atlas, a battleground for the Starcraft II World Championships

Used in GSL, GSTL, IPL, DreamHack, Assembly and more (200k+ spectators) https://tl.net/forum/sc2-maps/388872-2-df-atlas Dec 2012 - Nov 2013

# **Technical skills**

## **Programming**

Python, Matlab, SQL, C#, C++, C, Java, JavaScript

#### **Deep Learning**

PyTorch, TensorFlow

#### **Others**

Linux, Git, Azure, AWS, Docker, Conda, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Latex

#### Languages

**Danish** Native

**English** Professional

**German** Basic